なんば　むった
＜私達 宇宙飛行士候補生
アスキャンの次なる訓練は➡
The next training exercise for the astronaut candidates, or ASCANs,
カムバックコンペティション＞
is the Comeback Competition.
＜パラシュｰトの展開システムから
ローバーまでを作り➡
It's a contest where you compete to reach the goal
ゴールに正確に
到達できるかを競う大会だ＞
by building everything from the parachute deployment system to the rover.
＜私達 Ｅ班のサポート役は…＞
Each team received an advisor, and in Team E's case...
(ピコ)チッ クソが！
Damn.
ふあああ～あ～…｡
It's Pico Norton, an old fart of an engineer who doesn't plan on much advising.
＜まったくサポートする気のない
屁コキ技術者 ピコ･ノートン｡➡
ぱら
しかも完全な酔っ払い｡
一体 何モンだ？＞
And he's drunk to boot.
So who is he?
SPACE BROTHERS
You've always been in my heart
But you don't say a thing or even smile
We've always been together
We're ignorant, but we believe
All the time I spent with you
Felt like a dream
We connected the stars and drew pictures
To our hearts' content
Let our hearts, shivering in excitement,
Use the sky as a canvas
And merge to form an everlasting image
#56 Promise to Drink
ふぅ…相変わらず➡
Looks like you still
きん
表情筋を使ってねえツラだな
ビンス｡シワもねえし｡➡
don't know how to use your facial muscles.
Is that the secret to staying young?
ひけつ
若さの秘訣か？
君は ここ数年で ずいぶん髪が
減ったようだな ピコ｡
You've lost a considerable amount of hair over the past few years.
髪が減ったんじゃねえ｡
I haven't lost any hair.
My face is just bigger, especially the forehead.
顔の面積が増えたんだ｡上に｡
Wild Turkey, a double.
(ピコ)ワイルドターキー
ダブルでくれ｡
きかん
[TV](ｷｬｽﾀｰ)月からの帰還が
せまっています｡
They will soon return from the moon.
Three of the six astronauts currently on the moon
[TV](ｷｬｽﾀｰ)現在 月面に滞在中の
宇宙飛行士６人のうち➡
そな
３人が ２週間後の帰還に備え
シミュレーションを開始しました｡
are running simulations to prepare for their return in two weeks.
飲む前から酔ってる顔だな｡
You look drunk, and you haven't even started.
フッ…まあな｡
Yeah.
近頃 こいつ無しじゃ
落ち着かねえんだよ｡➡
I'm a nervous wreck when I'm sober these days.
Just between you and me...
ここだけの話な｡
Your reliance on the simplistic method of drinking to drown your fears
酒で恐怖心をごまかすという
とど
実に単純な発想に留まるあたり➡
suggests you haven't grown up at all.
ガキの頃と
レベルが変わってないな｡
恐怖心だぁ!?俺がか？
Drown my fears? Really?
せけん
そうだ｡良くも悪くも今 世間が
一番注目しているのは｡
Yes.
For better or worse, the world is currently focused
あんぴ
帰還するオリオンの安否だ｡
on Orion's safe return.
えいゆう
[TV](ｷｬｽﾀｰ)３人の英雄を亡くした
ひげき
のうり
悲劇が脳裏をよぎります｡
Their return invokes memories of the moment when we lost three heroes.
[TV](ｷｬｽﾀｰ)あの時と同じく
帰還船オリオンで➡
The astronauts will once again be using Orion for their reentry.
地球に帰ってきます｡
今回が事故以来 初めての➡
This will be the first reentry for a lunar mission since the accident,
月からの帰還ということで
きんちょう
関係者の間にも緊張が…｡
and many involved are getting nervous.
Damn it.
クソが！
ブライアン達の事故を➡
They're using Brian's accident to build hype!
あお
くだらねえ煽りに使いやがって｡
The lives of the three returning astronauts are in your hands.
帰ってくるあの３人の命を
背負わされてるんだ｡➡
その重圧が
恐怖に変わっている頃だろ ピコ｡
I presume that it's at the point where pressure has become fear, Pico.
It comes down to whether the parachute you designed will deploy properly or not.
君が仕込んだパラシュートが➡
ちゃんと開くかどうかに
かかっている｡
ふぅ～…俺がやったんだ｡
開くに決まってんだろ｡
I designed it.
It'll open.
(せりか)南波さん｡
Nanba.
あっ せりかさん｡
Serika...
Are you feeling better?
体調 大丈夫ですか？
はい もう完璧に｡
Yes, I feel terrific.
《あ いや…》
Wait.
⦅あ～ん⦆
⦅もああ…⦆
⦅もあ～ん⦆
I can play this card a little longer...
《もうちょっと引っ張れるかも
せりかさんが介抱してくれる➡
Enjoy some more happy time, with Serika taking care of me!
ハッピータイムを！》
あ あの 実は…｡
Actually...
あ よかったです！
That's great news!
ローバー作り 自動車開発をしてた
南波さんがいてくれたら➡
Having someone with automobile development experience will be a big help with the rover.
百人力ですから｡
はい！
Absolutely!
《いや これはこれで…アリ！》
Well, this also works.
(技術者)タイヤ部分には
ゴムは使わず➡
I recommend that you use a light, durable material such as plastic, rather than rubber, for the tires.
軽量で強いプラスチック製に
することを おすすめします｡➡
ゴムの方が
走りは安定しますが➡
Rubber allows for smooth driving, but you have to watch the weight.
重量に余裕が
なくなってしまうので｡
(ｱｽｷｬﾝ)これで進むんですか？
It'll actually run on those?
こんな風に作れば ﾌﾟﾗｽﾁｯｸ製でも
ちゃんと進みますよ｡
If you use this design, plastic wheels will work fine.
Ah, I understand...
(ｱｽｷｬﾝ)ああ なるほどね｡
They're so lucky.
いいな～｡
(ケンジ)他の班を担当する
技術者は➡
The engineers assigned to the other teams are helping with their designs.
ちゃんと作り方を
教えてくれるみたいだね｡
俺らの担当は
あの酔っ払いだからなぁ｡
Meanwhile, we're stuck with a drunk...
自分達だけで
やるしかなさそうだね｡
Looks like we're on our own.
ザマミロ 新記録だぜっ グフッ！
Take that, a new record!
何しにきてんだろ…｡
Why is he here?
にった
(新田)あのヤロウ…｡
Bastard.
Excuse me.
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)あの…何かアドバイス
もらえませんか？ピコさん｡
Could you offer us some advice, Pico?
About where we should start?
何から始めるべきとか｡
《おっ！いいぞ ケンジ！
俺もそれを聞こうと思ってた》
Nice, Kenji...
That's what I wanted to ask!
(ピコ)ヘッ そうだな➡
Sure, here's a tip...
じゃあ １個教えてやろう｡
俺に聞いている時点で➡
The moment you got stuck with me,
お前らには無理だ｡
your chances were shot.
《やっぱりダメか》
Guess it's no use.
(新田)ローバーの製作費として
さっき渡された600ドル｡➡
We've been given six hundred dollars to fund the rover's production.
これを どう使うかが
ポイントになってきそうだな｡
They're probably watching how we spend this money.
確かにね｡とりあえず訓練手順書の
ルールを よく読んで考えよう｡
True...
Let's start by reading the rules carefully.
だな｡
Yeah.
＜私達がこの訓練で作るものは
空中で放出され➡
During this training,
we will build a CanSat that will be launched and automatically navigate to the goal.
せいぎょ
自動制御で目的地に向かう
キャンサット＞
After the rover's release,
＜空中で放出されたあと
パラシュートを展開し…＞
the parachute is deployed.
Then the rover must find its way on its own.
＜自動制御で目的地へ
向かわなければならない＞
＜キャンサットは あらかじめ
用意されたロケットの中に➡
The CanSat will be placed in a rocket provided to us,
入れて打ち上げるため
寸法と重量に制限がある＞
so the dimensions and weight are limited.
The first step is to drop by a local hardware store and buy materials.
＜製作は ここの近くにある
ホームセンターで➡
適切な材料を選んで
買うところから始める＞
各班の製作費
支給される額が違うんだね｡
Each team received a different amount to spend.
(北村)えっ どこ？
最後のページに書いてある｡
Huh? Where does it say that?
It's on the last page.
あっ ほんとだ！
You're right!
サバイバルのゴール順で
違うわけか｡
It's based on the survival training ranks.
Ａ班は 800ドルも使えるんだ｡
Team A gets eight hundred dollars.
Eight hundred dollars.
800ドル…８万円弱か｡
Around eighty thousand yen?
We have about sixty thousand yen...
私達は６万くらいか｡
結構 不利な状況かもね｡
That's a serious disadvantage.
くぁ～…はぁ～…｡
I'd say there's more than one.
《たしかに不利 いろんな意味で》
ゲフッ…あ～ どうやら君らも➡
Sounds like you're the same as me.
俺と同じだな｡
(ピコ)スイッチが…オフだぜ｡
Your switch is set to off.
くちぐせ
そりゃピコの口癖だ｡➡
That's a phrase Pico likes to use.
スイッチがオンだの
オフだのってのはな｡➡
He's always talking about his switch being on or off.
あと あれだ｡人生はいつ
終わるかわかんねえから➡
Also,
he likes talking about how you never know when life will end.
どうのこうのっていうのも
よく言うね ピコは｡
(ケンジ)言ってました それ｡
言ってたね｡
He did mention that.
Yeah.
俺には ピコが
オンの時とオフの時との区別は➡
Well, I can't tell any difference with Pico's switch being on or off,
つかねえけどな｡
わかる奴が言うには➡
but those who can, claim he's a little more serious when his switch is on.
オンの時の方が ちょっとだけ
真面目になるらしいよ｡ハハハ…｡
ナサ
ＮＡＳＡの職員じゃ
ないんですか？
He isn't a NASA employee?
He's not.
違うよ 俺もピコも｡
俺達は デンバー社の職員だ｡
Neither am I.
We work
for Denver.
(技術者)言ってみりゃ➡
You could say
that we're one of NASA's subcontractors.
したう
ＮＡＳＡの下請けの技術者って
とこだな｡➡
主に帰還船オリオンの
開発を任されている｡➡
We primarily worked on Orion's reentry capsule.
ピコは パラシュートの
展開システムを開発･製造する➡
Pico is the project manager for the parachute deployment system.
サブプロジェクトの
ﾌﾟﾛｼﾞｪｸﾄ･ﾏﾈｰｼﾞｬｰ 総合責任者だ｡
He's in charge.
《パラシュｰトの責任者だって!?》
He's in charge of the parachute deployment system?
But he's a total mess...
《あんなグダグダで
ヨロヨロした人が…➡
なんでそんな超重要な
ポジションなんだ!?》
Why would they give him such an important job?
まさか 日々人達が帰りに乗る
オリオンのパラシュートも？
You can't mean the parachute system on Orion that Hibito and the others will use for reentry was...
ああ ピコの担当だ｡
Yeah.
Pico was in charge of it.
《大丈夫なのか!?》
Will it be okay?
あ あの…
もう１つ聞いていいすか？
U-Uh,
may I ask another question?
ブライアン達の事故が起こった
パラシュートは ピコさんが…｡
Was Pico in charge of the parachute system
for the accident of Brian's crew?
設計図を見つけました！
I found a blueprint.
Huh?
去年の大会に出場した人が➡
A participant from last year's contest uploaded it to the internet.
ネットにアップしていたんです｡
けいさい
写真も図面も掲載されてたんで➡
It included pictures and designs, so I printed everything out.
全部プリントアウトしました｡
ナイスだよ！さすが せりかさん｡
Nice job! Way to go, Serika!
ピコさんが教えてくれない以上
これに従って作っていくしか➡
Since Pico isn't going to help, we'll have to rely on this.
なさそうだな｡
いいですよね？ピコさん｡➡
Is that all right with you, Pico?
ネットを使用するなとは
どこにも書いていませんでしたよ｡
I didn't see any rules barring internet use.
勝手にどうぞ～｡
うん…ふあぁ～…｡
Knock yourselves out.
(ケンジ)よし 始めよう！
Okay, let's get started.
《フンッ 図面があるからといって
できるもんじゃねえんだよ｡➡
A blueprint won't be enough to finish the job.
パラシュート１つにしてもそうだ｡
そう 甘くない｡➡
Even to make something as simple as a parachute.
It isn't that easy.
甘くねえんだよ バカヤロウ》
It isn't that easy, fool.
たいは
(技術者)大破だよ 大破｡
It crashed.
What was the cause?
(技術者)原因は？
しせい
(技術者)姿勢制御できずに➡
The parachute got tangled when the capsule spun out of control.
から
パラシュートが絡まったんだ｡
ピコさん…｡
くそっ なんでだ!?
Pico...
Damn, why?
You kidding me?
マジかよ～！
ま～た絡まっちゃったの？
The parachute got tangled again?
ブライアン！
Brian!
Are you trying to give me a heart attack, Pico?
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)なかなかドキドキさせて
くれるじゃねえか ピコ｡
俺たちのクルーは
来年あれに乗るんだぜ？
My crew's going to be riding in that thing next year.
いやっ 違うんだ ブライアン｡
Wait, you misunderstand, Brian.
この試験は オリオンの重量や
大気の状態も含めて➡
Currently, we're running stress tests to see how Orion does with various payloads,
under different atmospheric conditions.
オリオンの性能の限界を
試すためのものなんだ｡➡
パラシュートシステムを
よりよくするために➡
We were anticipating a possible crash, to improve the parachute system.
ついらく
そうていない
墜落も想定内の試験だったんだ｡
じゃあ来年 俺はペシャンコに
ならなくてすむワケね｡
So you're saying I won't end up a pancake next year?
ああ 信じてくれ！
かえ
必ずアンタを無事に還す｡
Yeah, you can trust me.
I'll bring you back in one piece.
ブライアン…俺が本当にやりたい
事ってのは １つしかないんだ｡
Brian, there's only one thing I want to do.
無事に帰還した宇宙飛行士と
一緒に 酒を飲むこと！
To share a drink with the astronauts, once they return to Earth.
Okay.
オッケー
ＯＫ ピコ｡一緒に飲もう｡
Pico, we'll get a drink together.
現在
《当たったら 酒を一口飲んで良し
…という俺のルール》
If I hit it, I take a swig.
That's my rule...
フンッ！
イエス
っしゃあ‼ＹＥＳ！
Right on! Yes!
ウ～ッ…ウィ～‼
フンッ！
(技術者)ピコは ただのふざけた
ヨッパライじゃねぇぞ｡
Pico isn't just some crazy drunk...
あ～見えて
ちゃんとした技術者だ｡➡
He's a qualified engineer.
まず 考えてみてくれ｡
アポロで月に行った時代には➡
Look at it this way.
Back during the Apollo program, when we were going to the moon,
ちゃ～んと
パラシュートが開いて➡
we had parachutes that would open and bring astronauts back safely.
宇宙飛行士は
みんな無事に帰ってきた｡
なのになんで
最近のアレス計画じゃ➡
But lately, we've run into problems with Ares.
しばらくそれが
できなかったのか…｡➡
当時の技術者達が
ＮＡＳＡにもういなかったからだ｡
It's because none of those engineers are still around.
図面は残ってて それを参考に
作ってるハズなのに➡
They left behind the blueprints everyone's following,
but for some reason, it won't work.
なぜか うまくいかない｡
シャトル時代に ｸﾞﾗｲﾀﾞｰ帰還方式が
当たり前になっちまったからな｡
During the shuttle era, everyone grew accustomed to gliding landings...
NASA lost its know-how regarding parachutes.
パラシュート式のノウハウが
ＮＡＳＡになくなっちまった｡
でも ロシアで続いているソユーズ
はずっとパラシュート式ですよね｡
But the Russian Soyuz has always used parachutes.
Couldn't you ask them for assistance?
ロシアに教わることは
できなかったんですか？
ロシアもアメリカも 宇宙船や
ロケットに関する技術は➡
Russia and America keep their space and rocket technologies classified.
きみつ
特に 国家機密なのさ｡➡
互いに自分達の切り札を
見せ合うようなことはしていない｡
Neither side will reveal secrets to the other.
And America can't just swallow its pride after going to the moon with Apollo.
それに アメリカには
アポロ計画で月に行った➡
プライドってもんがあるからな｡
なるほど プライドか…｡
I see...
So it's a matter of pride.
(ﾛｰﾘｰ)⦅イッツ プラ～イド‼⦆
It's "pride"!
No good.
《ダメだ…ローリーのせいで
プライドって言葉の格が➡
Lowry cheapened the word "pride" for me.
だいぶ うすれてる…》
Then after all those failures, the engineer who developed a workable parachute system...
まあ とにかく そんな失敗に➡
しこうさくご
試行錯誤を繰り返して
やっと今の使える➡
パラシュートシステムに
仕上げた技術者が…｡
あのピコ･ノートンってわけだ｡
Was Pico Norton.
(技術者)その後もピコは
試験を続けたよ｡➡
Pico continued to run tests afterward.
もっと確実でより良いパラシュｰト
システムにするためにな｡➡
To ensure that the parachute system was as good as it could be.
Because he felt it was still unfinished.
あいつの中じゃ
まだ不完全だったんだな｡➡
But that was when
その途中でピコは
１度だけ想定外のミスをした｡
he made an unexpected mistake.
現在
(ピコ)お～い！
Hey!
(ピコ)なんだい君ら｡
What are you doing?
バッテリー切れか？➡
Battery dead?
ナマケモノでも
もうちょい動くぜ｡
Sloths move faster than you guys.
やる気がないなら やめちまえ｡
やるって言うんなら 動け！
If you have no motivation, give up now.
If you want to do to this, get moving.
Damn...
《チクショー！一番やる気
なさそうなくせに…》
He's the least motivated person in this room.
Pico is right.
ピコさんの言う通りだな｡
この図面を見ながら始めていこう｡
Let's start working off this blueprint.
まずは 自動制御のﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾐﾝｸﾞを
誰が担当するかだけど…｡
First, we need to decide who will program the navigation system.
(ｱﾏﾝﾃｨ)それなら私が｡
インドでは小学校から➡
I can handle that.
In India, programming is taught in grade school.
プログラミングを勉強しますから｡
I can also help.
あ…っ 私も少しなら｡
Okay, then Amanti and Kitamura will handle most of the programming.
(ケンジ)よし！じゃあ主に
プログラミングは➡
アマンティと北村さんに任せよう｡
じゃあ次は ローバーの製作担当➡
Next, who will build the rover?
アッハハ ムッ君は はずせないね｡
We have to put Mu there.
We've managed to assemble the body...
ボディらしきモノができてきたね｡
今日はここまでかな｡
I think we can call it a day.
明日も この図面通りに
ｽﾀﾋﾞﾗｲｻﾞｰとタイヤを作っていこう｡
Tomorrow, we'll build the stabilizer and tires.
他の材料は明日の朝買いに…｡
ちょっと待ってくれ ケンジ｡
We'll buy more materials in the morning—
Hold on, Kenji.
それじゃ ダメだ｡
This won't work.
結構 ぜいたくな素材を
ふんだんに使ってるんだよ コレ｡
We're using pretty expensive materials.
At this rate, we'll use up five hundred dollars.
このままいったら 合計で
５００ドル近く使っちゃうよ｡
俺らには６００ドル渡されてんだ｡
十分足りるだろ｡
We've been given six hundred.
That's more than enough.
いや…これだと
１機作るのが予算の限界だ｡
No, at this rate, we'll only have the money to build one.
失敗できない｡
Leaving no room for error.
It's better if we plan to build two, expecting one to get wrecked.
こわ
ぜんてい
失敗して壊れるの前提で
最低でも２機作れるくらいの➡
よゆう
余裕があったほうがいいよ｡ん？
しょうきょくてき
やけに消極的だな 南波｡
That's a pessimistic outlook.
モノ作りには 失敗することに
かける金と労力が必要なんだよ｡
When you build something, you must be ready to spend time and money on failure.
あ…っ ピーナッツか｡
A peanut?
The best materials won't always yield the best results.
いい素材を使っているモノが
いいモノとは限らねぇんだ｡
だけど…｡
However,
失敗を知って乗り越えたモノなら
それはいいモノだ｡
if you build something by improving on failure,
you'll end up with good results.
(ゲイツ)じゃあ 何だ｡ワザと失敗
したって言う気か ピコ｡
Are you saying the error was deliberate, Pico?
いえ ワザとではありません｡
報告書に書いた通り➡
No, it wasn't on purpose...
As the report states, we were anticipating a possible crash.
墜落も想定内｡性能の限界を
知るための試験だったんです｡
The test's purpose was to determine the capsule's limitations.
限界をさぐっていて
限界を知ったんだから➡
We had to push it to its limits in order to learn them.
あれはある意味
成功だったんです！
The test should be considered a success.
へりくつ
(ゲイツ)屁理屈はもういい｡➡
I've heard enough.
That may have worked last time,
前回はそうだったかもしれんが
今回の墜落は どう説明する？
but what about the most recent crash?
なかったぞ 試験手順書に｡
The manual doesn't mention anything about needing to test limits.
｢限界を知るための試験｣
なんて文字は｡
I'm very sorry...
申し訳ありません｡
今回の墜落はおそらく
単純な人的ミスによるもの｡
Most likely, this crash was caused by human error.
An inexcusable mistake...
あってはならないヒュｰマンエラｰが
原因と思われます｡
＜この時のミスさえなければと➡
I found myself regretting it many times.
のち
こうかい
後に何度も後悔した｡
後の調査で➡
Later, the investigation determined that one of the workers was left-handed.
原因はパラシュートを折りたたむ
作業員の中に１人だけ➡
左利きの者がいたことがわかった｡
たたむ方向にズレが生じ…＞
Meaning the parachute wasn't folded evenly.
As a result, the parachute got tangled,
＜本来 開くはずだった
パラシュートは からまりあい➡
あわ
数千万ドルが泡と消えた＞
wasting tens of millions in the process.
次は ちゃんと！
This won't happen next time!
悪いけど 次はないよ ピコ｡
Sorry, but there won't be a next time, Pico.
パラシュｰトのシステムに関しては
君のデンバー社ではなく➡
We've decided to go with NewAir, over Denver, for the parachute system.
ニューエアー社に
任せることになった｡
Wh-Wh-What was that?
な…っ なんだって!?
ニューエアー社は 確実な
パラシュートシステムを➡
NewAir has promised to deliver a safe parachute system at a lower price.
君らよりも安く仕上げられると
言っている｡申し分のない条件だ｡
We can't turn that down.
来年 ブライアン達が乗る
セス
ＣＥＳ-５０のオリオンには➡
We'll be using NewAir's parachute system
ニューエアー社の
とうさい
パラシュートを搭載する｡
when Brian's CES-51 crew rides Orion.
ちょっと待て！金がどうした！
乗せるのは命だぞ‼
Hold on!
This is about money?
Human lives are on the line!
人の命 預かってんだ！
金に糸目つけてんじゃねぇ‼
They're trusting you with their lives.
You can't let money sway you!
ク…クソが‼
Damn it!
It's too bad, Pico.
残念だぜ ピコ｡
お前の本気さは伝わってたからな｡
I could tell you were sincere...
I'm sorry, Brian.
(ピコ)すまない ブライアン｡
酒を飲む約束も守れずに｡
I won't be able to keep our promise to drink together.
What are you talking about?
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)何 言ってんだ｡
その約束は生きてるよ｡
Our promise isn't off.
When I get back, I'll get you drunk enough to forget all of this.
俺が帰ったら 今回のことなんか
忘れるぐらい飲み明かそうぜ｡
現在
You asked if Pico was responsible for the deaths of Brian's crew.
ブライアン達の事故機が➡
ピコの仕事だったかどうか…｡➡
答えはＮＯだ｡当時 ＮＡＳＡの
技術責任者だった男が➡
The answer is no.
The head NASA engineer at the time didn't understand Pico.
ピコを理解してなかったのさ！
もしピコがやってたなら…｡
If Pico had been in charge,
Brian would be alive now!
ブライアンは生きていた｡
俺はそう思ってるね｡
That's what I believe.
(技術者)ブライアン達が死んだ日
その夜➡
The night of the day that Brian died,
Pico went to the pub, as promised, alone.
それでもピコは１人で
約束のパブに行った｡
俺のおごりだ｡
飲んでくれ ブライアン｡
It's on me.
Cheers, Brian.
うっ…うっうっうっ…｡
Brian...
(ピコ)ブライアン…｡
As you place your hopes on the distant moon
And leave on your journey
You smile in spite of your loneliness
Because you believe in yourself
It doesn't matter if your wings don't match
Spread them out
As you
begin your long journey (try now) (try now)
I'm sure you can make it
Please don't hesitate
to move straight forward
You took
all your pain and sorrow (no more) (no more)
And turned it into your strength
So I'm sure even your destiny to fight many a battle
Is on your side
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#57 An Engineer's Switch
Five days until the competition ends.
＜コンペまで あと５日｡
課題は山積み＞
We have a lot to do.
(新田)＜パラシュートは開かない｡
ローバーは すぐ止まる＞
The parachute won't open.
The rover won't move.
＜ちょっとした壁に当たるだけで
ダメになるみたいだね＞
The second it bumps into a wall, it stops.
Just like me...
＜まるで俺じゃねぇか＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"An Engineer's Switch"